( BIRDS SQUAWKING )
( CAWING )
( WINGS FLUTTERING )
( CHIRPING )
( TWITTERING )
( SQUAWKING INTENSIFIES )
( CABLE CAR BELL DINGING )
( SQUAWKING CONTINUES )
( BOY WOLF WHISTLES )
( BIRDS SQUAWKING )
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
Hello , Mrs. MacGruder .
Oh , hello , Miss Daniels .
Have you ever seen so many gulls ? What do you suppose it is ?
There must be a storm at sea . That can drive them inland , you know .
I was hoping you 'd be a little late . You see , he hasn 't arrived yet .
- Oh , but you said 3 : 00 . - Oh , I know .
I know . I 've been calling all morning .
Oh , Miss Daniels , you have no idea .
They are so difficult to get . Really , they are .
We have to get them from India ,
when they 're just baby chicks , and then ...
This one won 't be a chick , will he ?
Certainly not . Oh , no , certainly not .
This will be a full-grown mynah bird . Full-grown .
And he 'll talk ?
Well , yes , of course he 'll ...
Well , no , you 'll have to teach him to talk .
I guess maybe I 'd better phone . They said 3 : 00 .
Maybe it 's the traffic . I 'll call .
Would you mind waiting ?
Well , maybe you 'd better deliver him .
Let me give you my address .
Oh , well , all right ,
but I 'm sure they 're on the way .
Would you mind if I called ?
No . All right .
MITCH : I wonder if you could help me .
What ?
I said , I wonder if you could help me .
Yes . What is it you 're looking for , sir ?
Lovebirds .
Lovebirds , sir ?
Yes . I understand there are different varieties .
Is that true ?
Well , yes , there are .
Well , these are for my sister for her birthday , you see ,
and as she 's only gonna be 11 ,
I wouldn 't want a pair of birds
that were too demonstrative .
I understand completely .
At the same time , I wouldn 't want them to be too aloof , either .
No , of course not .
Do you happen to have a pair of birds that are just friendly ?
Oh , I think so . Now , then , let me see .
Aren 't those lovebirds ?
No . Those are red birds .
I thought they were strawberry finches .
Yes . We call them that , too .
Here we are . Lovebirds .
Those are canaries .
Doesn 't this make you feel awful ?
Doesn 't what make me feel ...
Having all these poor , little innocent creatures caged up like this ?
Well , we can 't just let them fly around the shop , you know .
( CHUCKLING ) No , I suppose not .
Is there an ornithological reason
for keeping them in separate cages ?
Well , certainly . It 's to protect the species .
Yes , that 's important , especially during the molting season .
That 's a particularly dangerous time .
Are they molting now ?
Oh , some of them are .
How can you tell ?
Well , they get a sort of hangdog expression .
Yes , I see . Well , what about the lovebirds ?
Are you sure you wouldn 't like to see a canary instead ?
We have some very nice canaries this week .
All right .
All right . May I see it , please ?
Oh ! Oh !
Oh , what is it ? Oh !
MITCH : There we are .
- Oh , there . - Wonderful .
Back in your gilded cage , Melanie Daniels .
What did you say ?
I was merely drawing a parallel , Miss Daniels .
How did you know my name ?
A little birdie told me .
Good day , Miss Daniels . Madam .
Hey , wait a minute .
I don 't know you .
Ah , but I know you .
How ?
We met in court .
We never met in court or anyplace else .
That 's true . I 'll rephrase it . I saw you in court .
When ?
Don 't you remember one of your practical jokes
that resulted in the smashing of a plate-glass window ?
I didn 't break that window .
Yes , but your little prank did .
The judge should 've put you behind bars .
What are you , a policeman ?
I merely believe in the law , Miss Daniels .
And I 'm not too keen on practical jokers .
What do you call your lovebird story if not ...
Oh , I really wanted the lovebirds .
Well , you knew I didn 't work here . You deliberately ...
Right . I recognized you when I came in .
I just thought you might like to know
what it 's like to be on the other end of a gag .
What do you think of that ?
I think you 're a louse .
I am . Good day , Miss Daniels . Madam .
And I 'm glad you didn 't get your lovebirds .
Oh , I 'll find something else . See you in court .
Who was that man ?
I have no idea .
( INAUDIBLE )
They said the mynah bird would be here later this afternoon ,
if you care to come back .
No , you 'd better send him .
May I use this phone ?
Why , certainly .
Daily News ? It 's Melanie Daniels .
Could you get me the City Desk , please ?
Just a minute , Mrs. MacGruder .
Hello , Charlie . Melanie .
I want you to do a favor for me .
No , this is a small one .
Pressure you ? Why , Charlie , darling , would I try to pressure you ?
Would you call the Department of Motor Vehicles for me ?
Find out who owns this license plate ,
W-J-H-0-0-3 .
Yes , a California plate .
No . I 'll stop off in a little while . Is Daddy in his office ?
No , I don 't want to break in on a meeting . Tell him I 'll see him later .
Thank you , Charlie .
Do you have any lovebirds ?
Well , no , not in the shop , but I can order them for you .
How soon ?
Well , when would you want them ?
Immediately .
Well , I could probably have them here by tomorrow morning .
Would that be all right ?
That would be just fine .
( CHIRPING )
Miss , is that for Mitch Brenner ?
Yes .
He 's not home .
That 's all right .
He won 't be back until Monday , I mean , if those birds are for him .
- Monday ? - Yes .
I don 't think you should leave them in the hall , do you ?
Well ... Where did he go ?
Bodega Bay . He goes there every weekend .
Bodega Bay . Where 's that ?
Up the coast , about 60 miles north of here .
Sixty ...
It 's an hour and a half by freeway ,
or two hours if you take the Coast Highway .
Oh .
I 'd look after them myself , but I 'm going away , too .
I 'm awfully sorry .
( TIRES SCREECHING )
( BELL DINGS )
- Good morning . - Good morning .
I wonder if you could help me .
I 'll try my best .
I 'm looking for a man named Mitchell Brenner .
- Do you know him ? - Yeah .
- Where does he live ? - Right here , Bodega Bay .
Yes , I know , but where ?
Right across the bay there .
Where ?
Now , see where I 'm pointing ?
Yes .
See them two big trees across there ?
On the other side of the bay ? Yes .
- And the white house ? - Yes .
That 's where the Brenners live .
The Brenners ? Mr. and Mrs. Brenner ?
No . Just Lydia and the two kids .
The two kids ?
Yeah , Mitch and the little girl .
Oh , I see . How do I get down there ?
You follow the road around the bay ,
and that 'll take you right to their front door .
The front door . Is there a back road I can take ?
No . That 's the only road .
You see , I want to surprise them .
Oh .
I don 't want them to see me arrive .
It 's a surprise , you see .
Well , you could get yourself a boat
and cut right across the bay to their dock .
Where would I get a boat ?
Down by the Tides Restaurant .
Did you ever handle an outboard boat ?
Of course .
Want me to order one for you ?
Well , thank you .
- What name ? - Daniels .
Okay .
( SHOP BELL DINGS )
( DIALING )
I wonder if you could tell me ...
Yeah . Just hold it a minute , please .
The little girl 's name ?
The little Brenner girl ?
Yes .
Alice , I think .
Harry , what 's the little Brenner girl 's name ?
- HARRY : Lois . - SHOPKEEPER : Alice , isn 't it ?
No , it 's Lois .
It 's Alice .
Are you sure ?
Well , I 'm not positive , if that 's what you mean .
I need her exact name , you see .
Oh , just hold on one more minute , please .
In that case , I 'll tell you what you do .
You go straight through town till you see a little hotel on your left .
Then you turn right there .
- Now , you got that ? - Yes .
Near the top of the hill , you 'll see the school , and just beyond ,
a little house with a red mailbox .
That 's where Annie Hayworth , the schoolteacher , lives .
You ask her about the little Brenner girl .
Well , thank you .
Save yourself a lot of trouble . Name 's Alice for sure .
Can I have the boat in about 20 minutes ?
How much for the phone calls ?
Oh , it 's nothing .
Thank you .
( CHILDREN TALKING INDISTINCTLY )
( DOORBELL RINGS )
WOMAN : Who is it ?
Me .
Who 's " me " ?
- Miss Hayworth ? - Yes .
I 'm Melanie Daniels . I 'm sorry to bother you , but ...
Yes ?
The man at the post office sent me .
He said you could tell me the name of the little Brenner girl .
Cathy ?
The one who lives in the white house across the bay ?
That 's the one . Cathy Brenner .
He seemed sure it was either Alice or Lois .
Which is why the mail never gets delivered
to the right place in this town .
I 'm sorry . Smoke ?
Thank you .
Did you want to see Cathy about something ?
Well , not exactly .
Oh .
Are you a friend of Mitch 's ?
No , not really .
You know , I 've been wanting a cigarette for the last 20 minutes .
I just couldn 't convince myself to stop .
This tilling of the soil can become compulsive , you know .
It 's a very pretty garden .
Oh , thank you . Well , it 's something to do in your spare time .
There 's a lot of spare time in Bodega Bay .
Are you planning on staying long ?
No , just a few hours .
Then you 're leaving after you see Cathy ?
Well , something like that .
I 'm sorry . I don 't mean to sound so mysterious .
Actually , it 's none of my business .
Well , I better be on my way .
- Thank you very much . - Not at all .
Did you drive up from San Francisco by the coast road ?
Yes .
Nice drive .
It 's very beautiful .
Is that where you met Mitch ?
Yes .
I guess that 's where everyone meets Mitch .
Now you sound a bit mysterious , Miss Hayworth .
( CHUCKLES )
Do I ?
I don 't mean to . Actually , I 'm an open book , I 'm afraid .
( CHIRPING )
Or , rather , a closed one .
Oh , pretty . What are they ?
Lovebirds .
I see . Good luck , Miss Daniels .
Thank you . Can I get out this way ?
Go right around . It 'll take you back to the main road .
Thank you .
( STARTS ENGINE )
( SEAGULLS CAWING )
Do you have a boat for Miss Daniels ?
Yes , ma 'am .
It 's the one right below .
( CHIRPING )
( MOTOR STARTS )
( MOTOR STOPS )
( MOTOR CRANKING )
( MOTOR STARTS )
- Are you all right ? - Yes , I think so .
What do you suppose made it do that ?
That 's the damnedest thing I ever saw .
I don 't know . It seemed to swoop down at you deliberately .
Oh , you 're bleeding , too .
Let 's take care of that . Okay ?
That 's a girl .
Come on .
What happened , Mitch ?
- Gull hit her . - A gull ?
Let 's try up at the restaurant , all right ?
Might need a tetanus shot .
I had a booster before I went abroad last May .
( PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY )
What happened ?
Hello , Deke . Young lady cut herself .
Shall I call a doctor ?
No , I don 't think it 's that serious . Let 's see .
Helen , get some cotton and antiseptic .
You cut yourself outside , miss ?
Don 't worry , Deke . She did it in a boat .
Well , I had a man trip and fall in the parking lot once .
Sued me before I could bat an eyelash .
I don 't think Miss Daniels is gonna sue anybody .
Here .
Well , you 're the lawyer .
Thank you .
What 's that ?
Just some peroxide .
I 'll clean out the cut .
So you 're a lawyer .
That 's right .
Of course , I usually defend people , Miss Daniels ,
but if I were prosecuting ...
Do you practice here ?
Uh-uh . San Francisco . What are you doing up here ?
What kind of law ?
Criminal .
Is that why you want to see everyone behind bars ?
Oh , not everyone , Miss Daniels .
Only violators and practical jokers .
That 's right .
- Ow ! - Oh , sorry .
What are you doing up here ?
Didn 't you see the lovebirds ?
Oh , you mean , you came all this way to bring me those birds ?
To bring your sister those birds .
You said it was her birthday .
Besides , I was coming up anyway .
What for ?
To see a friend of mine . Careful .
Oh , sorry . Who 's your friend ?
Annie Hayworth , the schoolteacher .
Annie Hayworth .
Well , small world .
Yes .
How do you know Annie ?
We went to school together , college .
Did you ? Imagine that . How long are you staying up here ?
The weekend .
Well , I think the bleeding 's almost stopped . Why don 't you hold that on ?
So you came up to see Annie , huh ?
Yes .
I think you came up to see me .
Now , why would I want to see you of all people ?
I don 't know , but you must 've gone to a lot of trouble
to find out who I was and where I lived .
It was no trouble at all . I simply called my father 's newspaper .
Besides , I was coming up anyway . I 've already told you that .
You really like me , huh ?
I loathe you .
You have no manners . You 're arrogant , and conceited , and ...
I wrote you a letter about it , in fact , but I tore it up .
What did it say ?
None of your business .
I can 't say I like your seagulls much , either .
I come all the way up here to ...
But you were coming up anyway , remember ?
Mitch ?
I thought I saw your car . What are you doing in town ?
I had to acknowledge a delivery .
Of what ?
Mother , I 'd like you to meet Melanie Daniels . Miss Daniels , my mother .
How do you do ?
How do you do , Miss Daniels ? Acknowledge a what ?
A delivery . Miss Daniels brought us some birds from San Francisco .
For Cathy for her birthday . Where is she ?
Across at Brinkmeyer 's .
As a matter of fact , Miss Daniels is staying up here for the weekend ,
so I 've already invited her for dinner tonight .
Well , you did go to the trouble of bringing those birds .
MELANIE : Oh , I couldn 't possibly .
You did say birds ?
Yes , lovebirds .
Oh , I see .
MITCH : So we couldn 't let you get away
without thanking you in some small way .
And you haven 't met Cathy , and you are staying the weekend .
Well , yes , but ...
Well , you are , aren 't you ?
Certainly , but ...
MITCH : Then it 's all settled .
What time is dinner , Mother ?
7 : 00 , the same as usual .
I 'll pick you up . Where are you staying ?
With Annie , of course .
Oh , of course . How stupid of me . 6 : 45 ?
Annie may have made other plans . I 'll have to see .
Besides , I can find my own way .
You 're sure now ? You won 't hire a boat or anything ?
I 'm sure .
MITCH : 7 : 00 , then .
Maybe .
We 'll be waiting for you . How 's your head ?
Much better , thank you .
A gull hit me , Mrs. Brenner , that 's all .
( RINGING )
Oh , hi . Did you find her all right ?
Yes , I did .
I was wondering ...
That sign there .
Do you suppose I could have the room for just a single night ?
I was planning on renting it for a longer time ...
I would appreciate it .
I 've tried everywhere in town . They 're all full .
Well , all right . Got your bags in the car ?
( CHUCKLES ) Well , it 's utilitarian , I 'll say that .
I just picked up some things for the night at the general store .
You see , I hadn 't planned on staying very long .
Yes , I know . Did something unexpected come up ?
Yes . May I use your phone ? I 'd like to call home .
I just put some coffee on the stove .
( SEAGULLS CAWING )
Don 't they ever stop migrating ?
( CAWING )
( RINGS )
Hi !
Miss Daniels ?
Yes .
Oh , they 're beautiful !
They 're just what I wanted . Is there a man and a woman ?
I can 't tell which is which .
MELANIE : Well , I suppose so .
MITCH : Hello there . Annie had no plans , huh ?
MELANIE : No .
Fine . We 're very glad you could come . You hungry ?
- Reasonably . - Dinner 's just about ready .
We 've been out back looking at the chickens .
Something seems to be wrong with them .
There 's nothing wrong with those chickens , Mitch .
I 'm going to call Fred Brinkmeyer right now .
What good 's that gonna do ?
The chickens won 't eat .
He sold the feed to me , didn 't he ?
Caveat emptor , Mother . " Let the buyer beware . "
Whose side are you on ?
Merely quoting the law , dear .
Never mind the law .
This won 't take long , Miss ... Hello , Fred ? Lydia Brenner .
- I didn 't interrupt your dinner , did I ? - How about a drink ?
Thank you , I 'd love one .
Fred , that feed you sold me is no good .
The chicken feed .
Well , it 's just no good . The chickens won 't eat it .
They 're always hungry .
I opened a sack for them when I got home ,
and they just wouldn 't touch it .
You know chickens as well as I do , and when they won 't eat ,
there 's something wrong with what they 're being fed . That 's all .
No , they 're not fussy chickens .
Who ? What 's he got to do with it ?
Is that your father ?
Mmm-hmm . Please sit down .
Fred , I don 't care how many sacks of feed you sold him .
My chicken ...
Oh , I see .
Dan Fawcett .
This afternoon ?
Well , that just proves what I 'm saying ! The feed you sold us ...
Oh .
Well , maybe I 'd better go over and see him .
You don 't think there 's something going around , do you ?
No , never !
No , Fred , they don 't seem sick at all . They just won 't eat .
Uh-huh .
Well , I 'll try to go over and see him . Maybe he ...
All right . Thanks .
He had a call from Dan Fawcett a while ago .
His chickens won 't eat either .
It 's what you said , Mom . Mr. Brinkmeyer 's feed is no good .
No , Cathy . He sold Mr. Fawcett a different brand .
You don 't think they 're getting sick , do you , Mitch ?
I still don 't understand how you knew I wanted lovebirds .
Your brother told me .
Then you knew Mitch in San Francisco ? Is that right ?
No , not exactly .
Mitch knows a lot of people in San Francisco .
Of course , they 're mostly hoods .
Cathy !
Well , Mom , he 's the first to admit it .
He spends half his day in the detention cells at the Hall of Justice .
In a democracy , Cathy , everyone is entitled to a fair trial .
Your brother 's practice ...
Oh , Mom , please !
I know all that democracy jazz . They 're still hoods .
He has a client now who shot his wife in the head six times .
Six times ! Can you imagine it ?
I mean , even twice would be overdoing it , don 't you think ?
Why did he shoot her ?
He was watching a ball game on television .
What ?
His wife changed the channel .
Are you coming to my party tomorrow ?
I don 't think so .
I have to get back to San Francisco .
Don 't you like us ?
Oh , darling , of course I do .
Don 't you like Bodega Bay ?
I don 't know yet .
Mitch likes it very much . He comes up every weekend , you know ,
even though he has his own apartment in the city .
He says San Francisco 's like an anthill at the foot of a bridge .
I suppose it does get a little hectic at times .
Well , if you do decide to come , don 't say I told you about it .
It 's supposed to be a surprise party .
You see , they 've got this whole complicated thing figured out ,
where I 'm going over to Michele 's for the afternoon ,
and Michele 's mother will say that she has a headache .
Would I mind very much if she took me home ?
Then when I get home here , all the kids will jump out !
Oh , won 't you come ? Won 't you please come ?
I don 't think so .
She 's a charming girl , isn 't she , Mitch ?
MITCH : Hmm ? Yes .
Certainly pretty .
Mmm-hmm .
How long have you known her ?
Now , I told you , dear , we met yesterday .
In a bird shop .
She was selling birds ?
No , no . I just led her into believing that I believed she was , and then ...
Well , it 's all very complicated .
But she did buy the lovebirds ,
and then drove all the way out here .
- Mother . - Yes ?
Where did you go to law school ?
Forgive me .
I suppose I 'm just naturally curious about a girl like that .
She 's very rich , isn 't she ?
Yeah , I suppose so .
Her father 's part owner of one of the big newspapers in San Francisco .
You 'd think he could manage to keep her name out of print .
She 's always mentioned in the columns , Mitch .
Yes , I know .
She is the one who jumped into a fountain in Rome last summer , isn 't she ?
Yes .
I supposed I 'm old-fashioned .
I know it was supposed to be very warm there , but ...
Well , actually , the newspapers said she was naked .
Yes , I know , dear .
Of course , it 's none of my business ,
but when you bring a girl like that ...
Darling ?
Yes ?
I think I can handle Melanie Daniels by myself .
Well , as long as you know what you want , Mitch .
I know exactly what I want .
Be able to find your way back all right ?
Oh , yes .
Will I be seeing you again ?
San Francisco 's a long way from here .
I 'm in San Francisco five days a week
with a lot of time on my hands .
I 'd like to see you .
Maybe we could go swimming or something .
Mother tells me you like to swim .
How does Mother know what I like to do ?
I guess we read the same gossip column .
Oh , that . Rome .
Yeah , I really like to swim . I think we might get along very well .
In case you 're interested , I was pushed into that fountain .
Without any clothes on ?
With all my clothes on . The newspaper that ran that story
happens to be a rival of my father 's paper .
You were just a poor , innocent victim of circumstances ?
I 'm neither poor nor innocent ,
but the truth of that particular ...
The truth is , you 're running around with a pretty wild crowd , isn 't it ?
Yes , that 's the truth , but I was pushed into that fountain ,
and that 's the truth , too .
Uh-huh .
Do you really know Annie Hayworth ?
No . At least I didn 't until I came up here .
- So you didn 't go to school together ? - No .
- And you didn 't come up here to see her ? - No !
- You were lying ! - Yes , I was lying .
What about the letter you wrote me ? Is that a lie , too ?
No , I wrote the letter .
Well , what did it say ?
It said , " Dear Mr. Brenner .
" I think you need these lovebirds after all .
" They may help your personality . "
- That 's what it said . - But you tore it up ?
- Yes . - Why ?
Because it seemed stupid and foolish .
Like jumping into a fountain in Rome .
I told you what happened !
You don 't expect me to believe that , do you ?
Oh , I don 't give a damn what you believe !
- I 'd still like to see you . - Why ?
I think it might be fun .
That might 've been good enough in Rome , but it 's not good enough now .
- It is for me . - Well , not for me .
What do you want ?
I thought you knew .
I want to go through life jumping into fountains naked . Good night .
( BIRDS SQUAWKING )
( CHIRPING )
Miss Daniels , is that you ?
Yes .
Hi .
Is something wrong ? Is that cut beginning to bother you ?
No , it 's not the cut that 's bothering me .
Would you like some brandy ?
If you have some , I 'd love it .
I 'll get it . Why don 't you sit down , Miss Daniels ?
Oh , would you like a sweater or something , a quilt ?
No . No , thank you .
Won 't you call me Melanie ?
All right .
Thank you .
Gets a bit chilly here at night sometimes ,
especially if you 're over near the bay .
Well , how did your evening go ?
Did you meet Lydia ?
Or would you rather I changed the subject ?
I think so .
Well , how do you like our little hamlet ?
I despise it .
( CHUCKLES )
Well , I suppose it doesn 't offer much to the casual visitor ,
unless you 're thrilled by a collection of shacks on a hillside .
It takes a bit of getting used to .
Where are you from originally , Annie ?
San Francisco .
How did you happen to come up here ?
A friend invited me up for a weekend a long time ago .
Look , I see no reason for being coy about this .
It was Mitch Brenner . I guess you knew that anyway .
I suspected as much .
Well , you needn 't worry .
It 's been over and done with a long time ago .
Annie , there 's nothing between Mr. Brenner and me .
Isn 't there ?
Well , maybe there isn 't .
Maybe there 's never been anything between Mitch and any girl .
What do you mean ?
I think I 'll have some of that .
I was seeing a lot of him in San Francisco .
Then one weekend , he invited me up to meet Lydia .
When was this ?
Oh , four years ago , shortly after his father died .
Of course , things may be different now .
Different ?
With Lydia .
Did she seem a trifle distant ?
A trifle .
Well , then perhaps things aren 't quite so different .
You know , her attitude nearly drove me crazy .
When I got back to San Francisco ,
I spent days trying to figure out exactly what I 'd done to displease her .
Well , what had you done ?
Nothing .
I simply existed . So what 's the answer ? A jealous woman , right ?
A clinging , possessive mother ?
Wrong .
With all due respect to Oedipus ,
I don 't think that was the case .
Then what was it ?
Lydia liked me . That 's the strange part .
Now that I 'm no longer a threat , we 're very good friends .
Then why did she object to you ?
Because she was afraid .
Afraid you 'd take Mitch ?
Afraid I 'd give Mitch .
I don 't understand .
Afraid of any woman who would give Mitch
the one thing Lydia can give him , love .
That adds up to a jealous , possessive woman .
No , I don 't think so .
You see , she 's not afraid of losing Mitch .
She 's only afraid of being abandoned .
Someone ought to tell her she 'd be gaining a daughter .
( CHUCKLES )
No . She already has a daughter .
Well , what about Mitch ? Didn 't he have anything to say about this ?
Well , I can understand his position .
He 'd just been through a lot with Lydia after his father died .
He didn 't want to risk going through it all again .
Oh , I see .
So it ended . Not right then , of course .
We went back to San Francisco , saw each other now and then ,
but we both knew it was over .
Then what are you doing here in Bodega Bay ?
I wanted to be near Mitch .
Oh , it was over and done with , and I knew it , but ...
I still wanted to be near him .
You see , I still like him a hell of a lot ,
and I don 't want to lose that friendship , ever .
( PHONE RINGING )
Hello .
No , no , no , I wasn 't asleep .
Yes , just a little while ago .
Sure . Hold on .
It 's Mitch .
For you .
Hello ? Oh , yes , this is Melanie .
Fine , thank you .
No , no trouble at all . I simply followed the road .
Well ... there 's no need to apologize .
I can understand .
That 's very kind of you . No , I 'm not angry .
Well , I couldn 't . I have to get back to San Francisco .
No , I wouldn 't want to disappoint Cathy , but ...
I see .
All right . Yes , I 'll be there .
Good night , Mitch .
He wants me to go to Cathy 's party tomorrow afternoon .
I said I would .
It should be fun .
I 'll be there , too , to help .
Oh , it seems so pointless .
Well , I think I 'll go to sleep . It 's been a busy day .
My luggage .
That 's pretty . Where 'd you get that ? Brinkmeyer 's ?
Mmm .
Do you think I should go ?
Well , that 's up to you .
No , it 's really up to Lydia , isn 't it ?
Never mind Lydia . Do you want to go ?
Yes .
Then go .
Thank you , Annie .
( CLATTERING ) Oh .
Wonder who that can be .
Is someone there ?
Who is it ?
Look .
Poor thing . Probably lost his way in the dark .
But it isn 't dark , Annie .
There 's a full moon .
( CHILDREN CHATTERING AND LAUGHING )
ANNIE : Cathy , that 's very good . Very good .
Okay . Here we go .
Attagirl . Come on . Don 't let him get you .
( INAUDIBLE )
No , I really shouldn 't have any more . I 'm driving .
Well , actually , I 'm trying to get you to stay for dinner .
A lot of roast beef left over .
No , I couldn 't possibly . I have to get back .
All right .
- Cheers . - Cheers .
Seriously , why do you have to rush off ?
What 's so important in San Francisco ?
Well , I have to get to work tomorrow morning , for one thing .
You have a job ?
I have several jobs .
What do you do ?
I do different things on different days .
Like what ?
Well , on Mondays and Wednesdays ,
I work for the Travelers ' Aid at the airport .
Helping travelers ?
No , misdirecting them . I thought you could read my character .
On Tuesdays , I take a course in General Semantics at Berkeley ,
finding new four-letter words .
That 's not a job , of course ... You mean , you don 't have to ...
And on Thursdays , I have my meeting and lunch .
In the underworld , I suppose .
I shall disappoint you .
We 're sending a little Korean boy through school .
We actually raise money for it .
You see , Rome ...
That entire summer , I did nothing but ...
Well , it was very easy to get lost there .
So when I came back , I thought it was time I began ...
Oh , I don 't know , finding something again .
So , on Mondays and Thursdays , I keep myself busy .
What about Fridays ?
Fridays ? They 're free .
I sometimes go to bird shops on Fridays .
I 'm very glad you do .
A nice , innocent , little day .
Oh , yes .
I have an Aunt Tessa . Have you got an Aunt Tessa ?
Mine is very prim and straight-laced .
I 'm giving her a mynah bird when she comes back from Europe .
Mynah birds talk , you know .
Can you see my Aunt Tessa 's face ,
when this one tells us one or two of the words I 've picked up at Berkeley ?
You need a mother 's care , my child .
Not my mother 's .
Oh , I 'm sorry .
What have you got to be sorry about ?
My mother ? Don 't waste your time .
She ditched us when I was 11 and ran off with some hotel man in the east .
You know what a mother 's love is ?
Yes , I do .
You mean it 's better to be ditched ?
No . I think it 's better to be loved . Don 't you ever see her ?
( VOICE BREAKING ) I don 't know where she is .
Well , maybe I ought to go join the other children .
ANNIE : All right . Here we go . One ...
Two ...
Three ...
There you go .
( CHILDREN SQUEALING EXCITEDLY )
( CHILDREN LAUGHING )
BOY : Look ! Look !
Hey ! No touching allowed !
( SQUAWKING )
Oh !
( BIRDS SQUAWKING )
( CHILDREN SCREAMING )
( LOUD POP )
Help me get the children into the house .
There you go .
( SOBBING )
Have they gone , Mitch ?
I think so .
LYDIA : Is anyone hurt ?
WOMAN : Jenny got a scratch down her cheek , but it 's nothing .
That makes three times .
Mitch , this isn 't usual , is it ?
The gull when I was in the boat yesterday ,
the one at Annie 's last night , and now ...
Last night ? What do you mean ?
A gull smashed into Annie 's front door . Mitch , what 's happening ?
I don 't know . Do you have to go back to Annie 's ?
No . I have my things in the car .
Stay and have something to eat before you start back . I 'd feel a lot better .
Would you like some mustard with that ?
MELANIE : No , thank you .
Why didn 't Annie stay for dinner ?
Said something about going home
to take a call from her sister in the east .
- ( CHIRPING ) - What 's the matter with them ?
What 's the matter with all the birds ?
Where did you want this coffee ?
Here on the table , honey .
Hurry up with yours , Mitch .
I 'm sure Miss Daniels wants to be on her way .
I think you ought to stay the night , Melanie .
We have an extra room upstairs and everything .
That road can be a pretty bad one at night , too .
If I go across to Santa Rosa ,
I 'll come out on the freeway much earlier , won 't I ?
Yes , and the freeway is much quicker .
But she 'll be hitting all the heavy traffic going back to San Francisco .
( LOUD CHIRPING )
CATHY : Just listen to those lovebirds .
( CHIRPING STOPS ) ( TWITTERING )
MELANIE : Mitch .
( BIRDS SCREECHING )
Cover your faces ! Cover your eyes !
That 's a sparrow , all right .
We know what it is , Al .
Did you have a light burning or something ?
Yes , but there wouldn 't have been
that much light going up the chimney .
' Cause sometimes birds are attracted by light , you know .
Sure is a peculiar thing .
Well , all right , but we 've got to do something about it !
I don 't think I get you , Mitch . Do about what ?
MITCH : Well , the birds invaded the house .
AL : What 's more likely , they got in the room
and was just panicked . That 's all .
MITCH : All right , I 'll admit a bird will panic in an enclosed room ,
but they didn 't just get in . They came in , right down the chimney .
AL : My wife found a bird in the back seat of her car once .
Tell him about the party .
That 's right . We had a party here this afternoon for Cathy , for her birthday .
AL : How old is she ?
MITCH : Eleven ! In the middle of the party ,
some seagulls came down at the children !
Miss Daniels was attacked by a gull only yesterday .
AL : Yeah . Were the kids bothering the birds or something ?
' Cause if you make any kind of a disturbance near them ,
they 'll just come after you .
Al , the children were playing a game . Those gulls attacked .
AL : Now , Lydia , " attack " is a pretty strong word , don 't you think ?
I mean , birds just don 't go around attacking people
without no reason . You know what I mean ?
The kids probably scared them , that 's all .
These birds attacked .
You got quite a mess here , I 'll admit that .
Maybe you ought to put some screen on top of your chimney .
You want some help cleaning up ?
- MITCH : No . I can handle it . - ( GASPS )
It shouldn 't be too much of a job .
I 'll take Cathy up to bed .
I think I should stay , don 't you ?
MITCH : It would be nice if you could .
My things are in the car .
- Do you want to go with me ? - All right .
AL : Well , anything else I can do , Mitch ?
MITCH : No , thanks , Al .
We 'll be all right .
Good night , Lydia .
Sure is peculiar .
( SHOVEL GRATING )
LYDIA : Mitch . Mitch . Mitch !
MITCH : Yes , Mother ?
LYDIA : I 'm going to drop Cathy off now .
I 'll probably drive over to the Fawcett farm .
- MITCH : Okay . - ( VEHICLE STARTING )
MAN : Morning .
Good morning , George . Is Mr. Fawcett around ?
I think so , ma 'am .
Ain 't seen him this morning , but he ought to be in there .
Thanks .
Dan , are you home ?
( GASPING )
( CHOKING )
( STARTS ENGINE )
( SOBBING )
Mother !
What is it , dear ? What 's the matter ?
Al Malone , the deputy , just called .
He wants me over at the Fawcett place .
Some detectives from Santa Rosa will be there .
- Will it be all right ? - Yes .
I was just taking your mother in some tea .
Oh , be careful , please .
And you be careful .
( DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES )
( KNOCKING )
LYDIA : Mitch ?
No , it 's me , Mrs. Brenner .
I thought you might like some tea .
Oh . Thank you .
Where 's Mitch ?
Al Malone wanted him out at the Fawcett farm .
Why ? Didn 't Al believe my story ?
He was calling from the farm .
Then he saw .
Oh , he must have .
They sent for the Santa Rosa police .
What good will they do ?
Do you think Cathy 's all right at the school ?
Yes , I 'm sure she 's fine .
Do I sound very foolish to you ?
Oh , no .
I keep seeing Dan 's face .
And they have such big windows at the school .
All the windows are broken in Dan 's bedroom .
All the windows !
Try not to think about that .
I wish I were a stronger person .
I lost my husband four years ago , you know .
It 's terrible how you depend on someone else for strength , and then
suddenly all the strength is gone , and you 're alone .
I 'd love to be able to relax sometime .
I 'd love to be able to sleep .
Do you think Cathy 's all right ?
Annie 's there .
She 'll be all right .
I 'm not like this , you know ? Not usually .
I don 't fuss and fret about my children .
When Frank died ...
You see , he understood the children . He really understood them .
He had the knack of entering into their world and becoming part of them .
That 's a very rare talent .
Yes .
Oh , I wish , I wish , I wish I could be like that .
I miss him .
Sometimes , even now , I wake up in the morning and I think ,
" I must get Frank 's breakfast . "
And I get up , and there 's a very good reason for getting out of bed ,
until , of course ,
I remember .
I miss talking to him .
Cathy 's a child , of course , and Mitch ...
Well , Mitch has his own life .
I 'm glad he stayed here today .
I feel safer with him here .
Would you like to rest now ?
No .
No , don 't go .
I feel as if I don 't understand you at all ,
and I want so much to understand .
Why , Mrs. Brenner ?
Because my son seems to be very fond of you ,
and I don 't quite know how I feel about it .
I don 't even know if I like you or not .
Is that so important , your liking me ?
Well , yes . I think so .
Mitch is important to me .
I want to like whatever girl he chooses .
And perhaps if you don 't ?
Well , then I don 't think it 'll matter very much to anyone but me .
Oh , I think it would also matter to Mitch .
Mitch has always done exactly what he wanted to do .
But , you see ,
I don 't want to be left alone .
I don 't think I could bear to be left alone !
Oh , forgive me .
This business with the birds has upset me .
I don 't know what I 'd do if Mitch weren 't here .
Why don 't you try to sleep now , Mrs. Brenner ?
I wish I was stronger .
Do you think she 's all right ?
Do you think she 's all right at the school ?
Would you like me to go for her ?
Oh , I couldn 't ask it .
Oh , I don 't mind , really .
Would you ?
I 'd feel so much better .
I 'll go right now .
Melanie ?
Thanks for the tea .
( CHILDREN SINGING )
I married my wife in the month of June
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Now , now , now
I brought her home by the light of the moon
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Hey , donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee , wallow-tee Now , now , now
She combs her hair but once a year
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Now , now , now
With every stroke She shed a tear
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Hey , donnie-dostle-tee
Rustical quality Ristle-tee , rostle-tee
Now , now , now
I brought her home by the light of the moon
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Hey , donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee , wallow-tee Now , now , now
She combed her hair but once a year
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Now , now , now
With every stroke She shed a tear
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Hey , donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee , wallow-tee Now , now , now
She swept up her floor but once a year
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Now , now , now
She said that brooms were much too dear
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Hey , donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee , wallow-tee Now , now , now
She churns the butter in her dad 's old boot
Ristle-tee , Rostle-tee Now , now , now
And for a dash She 'd use her foot
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Hey , donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee , wallow-tee Now , now , now
The butter it came out all grizzle-y gray
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Now , now , now
The cheese it took legs and ran away
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Hey , donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee , wallow-tee Now , now , now
She let the critter get away
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Hey , donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee , wallow-tee Now , now , now
I asked my wife to wash the floor
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Now , now , now
She gave me my hat and she showed me the door
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Hey , donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Now , now , now
I married my wife in the month of June
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Now , now , now
I brought her home by the light of the moon
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Hey , donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee , wallow-tee Now , now , now
She combed her hair but once a year
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Hey , donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety Rustical quality
Willow-tee , wallow-tee Now , now , now
Ristle-tee , rostle-tee Now , now , now
ANNIE : All right , children . Now , please put your song books away ,
then stand up alongside your desks .
We 'll go out for recess as soon as everybody gets ready .
We are not going into the playground
until everybody has quieted down .
- Close that door . Quickly . Please . - What ?
- What is it ? - Look .
We 've got to get the children out of here .
( CHILDREN TALKING INDISTINCTLY )
( SHUSHING ) All right , children . Now , quiet .
Quiet . Miss Daniels would like to see
how we conduct ourselves during a fire drill .
( EXCLAIMING IN PROTEST )
I would like you to show her how quiet and obedient you can be .
Oh , we 're going out of school now .
CHILDREN : Leave school ?
We want those of you who live nearby to go directly home .
CHILDREN : Home ?
I want the rest of you to go down the hill all the way to the hotel .
Now , is that clear ?
CHILDREN : Yes , Miss Hayworth .
Melanie ?
I want you to go as quietly as possible .
Do not make a sound until I tell you to run .
Then run as quickly as you can .
Now , does everybody understand ?
CHILDREN : Yes , Miss Hayworth .
All right , John , you lead the way .
( LOUD FLUTTERING )
( BIRDS SHRIEKING )
( CHILDREN SCREAMING )
( CAWING )
( SCREAMING )
( SQUAWKING )
Cathy ! Cathy !
( CRYING )
( HONKING )
Well , Daddy , there were hundreds of them .
No , I 'm not hysterical .
I 'm trying to tell you this as calmly as I know how .
All right , Daddy . Yes , Daddy .
Well , just now . Not 15 minutes ago .
At the school .
No , I don 't . Just a minute . What 's the name of the school ?
Just the Bodega Bay School .
The Bodega Bay School .
Well , I don 't know how many children , 30 or 40 .
No , the birds didn 't attack until the children were outside the school .
Help you , Mrs. Bundy ?
I need some change , Mr. Carter .
Crows , I think .
Well , I don 't know , Daddy .
Is there a difference between crows and blackbirds ?
There is very definitely a difference , miss .
Thank you .
They 're different , Daddy .
Well , I think these were crows .
Well , yes . Hundreds of them .
Yes , they attacked the children . Attacked them !
Well , I don 't know when , but I simply can 't leave now , Daddy .
All right . Yes . Good-bye .
They 're both perching birds , of course , but quite different species .
The crow is Corvus brachyrhynchos ,
and the blackbird is Euphagus cyanocephalus .
Thank you .
You have the number at the Fawcett farm ?
Right here in this book , miss .
I can 't see that it makes any difference , Mrs. Bundy .
Crows or blackbirds ,
if the school was attacked , that 's pretty serious .
I hardly think that either species
would have sufficient intelligence to launch a massed attack .
Their brainpans are not big enough to ...
I just came from the school , madam .
I don 't know anything about their brainpans , but ...
Well , I do . I do know .
Ornithology happens to be my avocation .
Birds are not aggressive creatures , miss .
They bring beauty into the world .
It is mankind , rather , who ...
WAITRESS : Sam ! Three southern fried chicken .
Baked potato on all of them .
Yes , may I speak to Mitch Brenner , please ?
Yes , I 'll wait .
It is mankind , rather , who insists upon
making it difficult for life to exist upon this planet .
Now , if it were not for the birds ...
Mrs. Bundy , you don 't seem to understand .
This young lady said there was an attack on the school .
- Impossible ! - Oh , Mitch ?
Oh , I 'm glad I caught you .
Something terrible has ...
It 's the end of the world !
Two Bloody Marys , Deke .
What actually happened at the school ?
Bunch of crows attacked the school kids .
It 's the end of the world . " Thus saith the Lord God
" unto the mountains and the hills ,
" and the rivers and the valleys .
" Behold I , even I ,
" shall bring a sword upon you ,
" and I will devastate your high places . "
Ezekiel , chapter six .
WAITRESS : " Woe unto them that rise up early in the morning ,
" that they may follow strong drink . "
Isaiah , chapter five . It 's the end of the world .
I hardly think a few birds are going to bring about the end of the world .
These weren 't a few birds .
I didn 't know there were many crows in Bodega Bay
this time of year .
The crow is a permanent resident throughout its range .
In fact , during our Christmas count , we recorded ...
How many gulls did you count , Mrs. Bundy ?
MRS. BUNDY : Which gulls , Mr. Sholes ? There are several varieties .
The ones who 've been playing devil with my fishing boats .
Have you had trouble with gulls ?
One of my boats did , last week .
This young lady was hit by a gull only Saturday .
Deke , I 'm still waiting for those Bloody Marys .
DEKE : Coming right up .
Could you ask them to lower their voices , please ?
They 're frightening the children .
A whole flock of gulls nearly capsized one of my boats .
Practically tore the skipper 's arm off .
You 're scaring the kids . Keep it low .
All right .
Yeah , well , he 's scaring me , too .
Are you trying to say that all these ...
Nah , that sounds impossible , Sebastian .
Deke , look , I 'm just telling you what happened to one of my boats .
The gulls were after your fish , Mr. Sholes .
Really , let 's be logical about this .
What were the crows after at the school ?
What do you think they were after ? Miss ...
Daniels . I think they were after the children .
For what purpose ?
To kill them .
Why ?
I don 't know why .
I thought not .
Birds have been on this planet , Miss Daniels ,
since Archaeopteryx , 140 million years ago .
Doesn 't it seem odd that they 'd wait all that time
to start a war against humanity ?
No one called it a war .
Scotch , light on the water .
You and Mr. Sholes seem to be implying as much .
Who said anything about a war ? All I said , some gulls ...
WAITRESS : Want some more coffee ? No .
... came down on one of my boats .
They could have been after the fish , just like you said .
The Captain should have shot at them . Huh ?
Gulls are scavengers , anyway . Most birds are .
Get yourselves guns and wipe them off the face of the Earth !
( CHUCKLES ) That would hardly be possible .
Why not , Mrs. Bundy ?
Because there are 8,650 species
of birds in the world today , Mr. Carter .
It is estimated that 5,750,000,000 birds
live in the United States alone .
The five continents of the world ...
Kill them all . Get rid of the messy animals .
... probably contain more than 100 billion birds .
It 's the end of the world .
Those gulls must have been after the fish .
MRS. BUNDY : Of course !
Hurry up , children . Finish your lunch .
Are the birds gonna eat us , Mommy ?
Hell , maybe we 're all getting a little carried away by this .
Admittedly , a few birds did act strange ,
but that 's no reason to believe that ...
I keep telling you , this isn 't a few birds .
These are gulls , crows , swifts ...
I have never known birds of different species to flock together .
The very concept is unimaginable .
Why , if that happened , we wouldn 't have a chance !
How could we possibly hope to fight them ?
We couldn 't , you 're right .
You 're right , Mrs. Bundy .
What 's the matter ? Something wrong out here ?
We 're fighting a war , Sam .
A war ? Against who ?
Against birds !
I 'm glad you all think this is so amusing .
You 've frightened the children half out of their wits .
If the young lady said
she saw the attack at a school , why don 't you believe her ?
What attack ? Who attacked the school ?
WOMAN : Birds did . Crows .
You 're all sitting around here debating !
What do you want them to do next ? Crash through that window ?
GIRL : Mommy !
Shh . Put on your coat .
Why don 't you all go home , lock your doors and windows ?
What 's the fastest way to San Francisco ?
The freeway , ma 'am .
How do I find it ?
I 'm going out that way , lady . You can follow me .
WOMAN : Well , then let 's leave now .
Haven 't finished my drink yet .
I got here as fast as I could . Where 's Cathy ?
She 's with Annie . She 's all right .
Al , why aren 't you over at the school , where the attack was ?
' Cause I just got back from Dan Fawcett 's place , that 's why .
He was killed last night by birds .
What ?
Now , hold it , Mitch . You don 't know that for a fact .
What are the facts , Mr. Malone ?
The Santa Rosa Police think it 's a felony murder .
They think a burglar broke in , killed him .
How do you explain the dead birds all over the floor ?
Santa Rosa Police figure they got in after the old man was killed .
Were the Santa Rosa Police at your school today ?
Are you coming ?
Now take it easy , lady .
There isn 't a bird anywhere in sight !
" Look at the birds of the air . They do not sow or reap .
" Yet your heavenly Father feeds them . "
Say , something like this happened in Santa Cruz last year .
The town was just covered with seagulls .
Will you please finish your drink ?
That 's right , sir . I recall it .
A large flock of seagulls got lost in a fog ,
and headed into the town where all the lights were .
They made some mess , too , smashing into buildings and everything .
They always make a mess .
The point is that no one seemed to be upset about it .
They were all gone next morning ,
just as though nothing at all had happened .
Poor things .
I 'm leaving ! Are you coming ?
All right , all right !
Well , hope you folks figure this thing out !
It 's the end of the world !
I better get back to the cannery . What do I owe you , Deke ?
Sebastian , hold it a minute .
I don 't want to be an alarmist about this ...
No one ever said you were , Mitch .
I think we 're in real trouble .
I don 't know how this started , or why ,
but I know it 's here and we 'd be crazy to ignore it .
To ignore what ? The " bird war " ?
Yes , the " bird war . "
The bird attack , plague ... Call it what you like ,
they 're massing out there some place ,
and they 'll be back . You can count on it .
Ridiculous .
Come here .
Unless we do something right now ,
unless we get Bodega Bay on the move , they ...
Look , Mitch .
Even if this is true , even if all the birds ...
Don 't you believe it 's true ?
No , Mitch , frankly I don 't .
There 's no reason . I ...
Well , it 's happening . Isn 't that a reason ?
I like Bodega Bay as well as the next man ...
Fine , then help me .
You 're an important man in this town . If you help , they all will .
SEBASTIAN : Help how ? What do you want to do ?
MITCH : Mrs. Bundy said something about Santa Cruz .
( GULL CAWING )
About seagulls getting lost in a fog
and flying in towards the lights .
SEBASTIAN : We don 't have fog this time of year !
MITCH : Make our own fog !
SEBASTIAN : How do you figure to do that ?
MITCH : We can use smoke pots , the way the Army uses them .
MELANIE : Look !
( SEAGULL CRYING )
They 're attacking again . Melanie , you stay in here . Come on , Al !
( SEAGULLS CAWING )
Look out !
Look at the gas . That man 's lighting a cigar !
Hey , you ! Watch out ! Don 't drop that match !
Get out of there !
- Mister , run ! - Watch out !
Look out ! Look out ! Watch out !
( ALL SHOUTING )
( PEOPLE CLAMORING )
( CALLING )
( SCREECHING )
( SCREAMING )
MAN : Hey !
( SIREN WAILING )
( SHRIEKING )
Why are they doing this ?
They said when you got here , the whole thing started !
Who are you ? What are you ?
Where did you come from ?
I think you 're the cause of all this .
I think you 're evil ! Evil !
( GASPS )
Oh , God !
I think they 're going !
We can get Cathy at Annie 's now .
- The crows again . - Shh !
( CAWING )
Come on .
( WINGS FLUTTERING )
Oh , no . Stay here . Stay here .
( GASPS AND SCREAMS )
( SOBBING )
Cathy ! Where 's Cathy ?
( CATHY SOBBING )
Mitch , don 't !
Oh , don 't leave her there , Mitch .
( MELANIE SOBBING )
( DOOR CLOSES )
( WHISPERS ) Come on .
( SOBS )
Shh !
( LOUD CAWING )
( STARTS ENGINE )
When we got back from taking Michele home ,
we heard the explosion
and we went outside to see what it was .
All at once the birds were everywhere !
All at once she pushed me inside ,
and they covered her !
Annie ... She pushed me inside !
( HAMMERING )
Give me another one , darling .
How long have they been gathering there ?
Oh , about 15 minutes .
Seems like a pattern , doesn 't it ?
They strike , then disappear , and then start massing again .
Doesn 't look so very different , does it ?
A little smoke hanging over the town , otherwise ...
You want to try your father again ?
No , I tried a little while ago . The phone 's dead .
- Still got power , haven 't we ? - Yes .
LYDIA : Mitch , I 'm getting something on the radio .
Come on .
I can 't get any of the local stations .
I think this is San Francisco .
MAN ON RADIO : " ... and the work of a team of professionals . " End quote .
In Bodega Bay early this morning , a large flock of crows
attacked a group of children who were leaving the school during a fire drill .
One little girl was seriously injured
and taken to the hospital in Santa Rosa ,
but the majority of children reached safety .
We understand there was another attack on the town ,
but this information is rather sketchy .
So far , no word has come through
to show if there have been further attacks .
On the national scene today , in Washington ...
Well , is that all ?
I 'll have to get some more wood in . Mustn 't let this fire go out .
Did you get the windows in the attic , Mitch ?
Yes , I got them all , dear .
When do you think they 'll come ?
I don 't know .
If there are bigger birds , Mitch , they 'll get into the house .
Well , it 's just a chance we 'll have to take .
Maybe we ought to leave .
No , not now ! Not while they 're massing out there .
When ?
We 'll just see what happens .
- Where will we go ? - I don 't know .
I think we 're safe here for the time being .
Let 's get the wood in now .
What happens when you run out of wood ?
I don 't know ! We 'll break up the furniture .
You don 't know !
You don 't know ! When will you know ? When we 're all dead !
If only your father were here ...
( CATHY SOBBING )
I 'm sorry . I 'm sorry , Mitch .
Make yourself some coffee , won 't you ?
" In assuming the tasks of the presidency ,
" I said that few generations ... "
Where are they heading ?
Somewhere inland .
Santa Rosa ?
Maybe .
Come on . Let 's get the wood .
Mitch ? Can I bring the lovebirds in here ?
No !
CATHY : But , Mom , they 're in a cage .
They 're birds , aren 't they ?
Let 's leave them in the kitchen , huh , honey ?
Mitch , why are they doing this , the birds ?
We don 't know , honey .
Why are they trying to kill people ?
I wish I could say .
( SHUDDERING SOFTLY )
I 'm sick , Melanie .
I want to ...
I 'll go with you .
( CATHY COUGHING )
( DOOR OPENS )
( BIRDS TWITTERING )
( WINGS FLUTTERING )
( CROWS CAWING )
( LOUD CAWING )
( HIGH-PITCHED CHIRPING )
( BIRDCALLS INTENSIFYING )
( GLASS SHATTERING )
( LOUD SCREECHING )
( BIRDS SCREECHING )
( RUMBLING )
( PECKING )
( BIRDS SHRIEKING )
( PECKING CONTINUES )
( BIRD SCREECHES )
( SOUNDS DIMINISH )
They 're going .
( SCREECHES FADING )
( CAWING STOPS )
( WINGS FLUTTER )
Mitch ?
( GASPS )
( SCREECHING )
( WHIMPERING )
( MOANING )
Oh , Mitch !
Get Cathy and Lydia out of here .
MITCH : Melanie ! Melanie !
( BIRDS SHRIEKING )
Melanie !
Oh , poor thing ! Poor thing !
Listen , get some water , bandages , and antiseptic . Quickly !
Bandages . It 's terrible .
Cathy , get some brandy .
No , no , no ! No , no , it 's all right .
No , it 's all right , it 's all right , it 's all right .
It 's all right . It 's all right . No .
- ( GASPING ) - ( SHUSHING )
Cathy , get the lamp .
( SIGHS ) We 've got to get her to a hospital .
We can 't , Mitch . There 's no place we can go .
There 's San Francisco .
We 'd never make it .
We have to try .
We 'll go by way of Bay Hill Road .
Then we don 't have to go through town .
We can 't stay here . She needs help !
I 'm frightened . Terribly frightened .
I don 't know what 's outside there .
We better get started before another attack comes .
We 'll take Melanie 's car . That 'll be faster than the truck .
Can you finish the bandaging ?
I 'll try .
All right .
LYDIA : Mitch ? See if you can get anything on the car radio .
( SOFT COOING )
( FLUTTERING )
( CAWING )
( LOW CLATTER )
( SWITCHING STATIONS )
ANNOUNCER : The bird attacks have subsided for the time being .
Bodega Bay seems to be the center ,
though there are reports of minor attacks
on Sebastopol and a few on Santa Rosa .
Bodega Bay has been cordoned off by roadblocks .
Most of the townspeople have managed to get out ,
but there are still some isolated pockets of people .
No decision has been arrived at yet as to what the next step will be ,
but there 's been some discussion as to whether the military should go in .
It appears that the bird attacks come in waves ,
with long intervals between .
The reason for this does not seem clear as yet .
( STARTS ENGINE )
( MOTOR TURNING OVER SLOWLY )
( SHUTS OFF MOTOR )
( HAND BRAKE CLICKS )
Did you hear anything on the radio ?
It 's all right . Come on .
( TURNS DOOR KNOB )
( GULL CRYING )
No . No !
( HUSHING )
Mitch ?
Shh .
Stay there .
Can I bring the lovebirds , Mitch ?
They haven 't harmed anyone .
All right . Bring them .
( STARTS ENGINE )
( BIRD CAWING INTENSIFIES )